# Tamás Szirbucz - Freelance Software Engineer



I started my career as Software Engineer in 2008. I gained experience in several fields: embedded systems, compilers, IT security and web application development. On my last workplace I worked as a Lead Java Engineer, where I had the chance to improve my leadership skills as well. I'm a freak of code quality and performance, therefore I always take care about testing and measurement, since what is not measured, can not be controlled.



+36 70 411 3157





# **Expertise**

Java Spring Framework Spring Data Spring Security JPA JUnit MySQL MongoDB HA-Proxy Hazelcast Kafka AngularJS (ReactJS (Selenium) (Performance optimization) (GDPR (Clean Code) (Object Oriented Design) (Architecture Design

Continous Deployment HTML5 CSS3 Agile

### **Work Experience**

**EPAM Systems - Lead Software Engineer** (2016-05-02 - 2018-10-31)

I led the development of a performance review tool with Java Spring based back-end and AngularJS based front-end. We used Kanban methodology and continous deployment with Unit-, Integration-, E2E- and manual tests, static analysis, code coverage, style check and code review in its pipeline. We worked in cooperation with remote OA team and management.

- Massive performance improvement
- GDPR compliance
- o Extend CD pipeline with Unit test coverage
- o Introduced Apache Kafka and moved all external APIs to it
- Change JSP parts to Angular front-end

#### Balasys IT Security Kft - Software Engineer (2014-09-01 - 2016-04-29)

Application layer proxy firewall

- Improvement of the user interface (GTK)
- o Extended in-house build tool with useful features
- o Found a "wrong size of NULL" bug in a Linux kernel lib
- Worked on Content Vectoring interface.

### Hightec EDV-Systeme GmbH - Software Engineer (2013-09-01 - 2014-07-31)

Development of GCC compiler backends for several embedded architectures.

- o Implement XML export of linker map and objdump
- o Introduced instruction set of new CPU version into our assembler
- o Developed compile time optimizations

#### Hightec Hungary Kft - Software Engineer (2011-03-01 - 2013-08-30)

Development of GCC compiler backends for several embedded architectures.

- o Introduced support of new CPU vendor
- Actively participated in the ISO-26262 audit of the tool

#### Department of Software Engineering, University of Szeged - Software Engineer (2008-05-05 - 2011-02-28)

Implement Procedural Abstraction compiler optimization

o 10-20% less binary size on popular open source projects.

Multifloor blueprint display integration with Open Street Maps

- C# & ASP.Net administration module for add and set position of blueprints
- Extended JS Map tool with controller for changing floors

Development of Webkit browser engine

- JIT optimizations
- Performance measurement

Sensor network for check state of floodlight

- Kernel module for own sensor HW
- o Bash scripts to collect sensor data from several nodes into one XML

# **Education & Training**

# Program Designer Mathematician, Master - University of Szeged (2005-2011)

- Java, C/C++, C#, HTML, CSS, XML
- Databases (SQL, PL/SQL, normalization)
- Software Engineering Processes
- Formal Languages and Automata
- Artificial Intelligence
- Image Processing

- Software Metrics

- Sottware Metrics
   Reverse Engineering
   Refactoring
   Machine Learning
   Natural Language Processing
   Teaching experience:

   Programming Languages (Smalltalk, Haskell, Prolog, Occam)
   Basics of Programming (C)
   Operating Systems (Bash & Bat scripting)
   Parallal Programming (Java concurrency, Occam, PVM)

  - Parallel Programming (Java concurrency, Occam, PVM)

# Java Academy - EPAM Systems (2016)

- Java fundamentals
  Spring Framework / MVC / Data / Security
  Hibernate, JPA, SQL
  OOP Design Patterns and Principles
  Web Application Development
  Building Web Services
  Unit testing, Mocking, TDD
  Clean Code
  Agile Methodologies

- Agile Methodologies
- Front-End technologies
- Version Control and CI

#### Introduction to Management - EPAM Systems (2017)

- Leadership and Team Building
- Motivation
- Time Management
- NegotiationProject and Delivery Management